HR/PAYROLL COORDINATOR

Professional Summary

Over 4 yrs experience in the field of corporate contract management on a global basis. Good knowledge in drafting, vetting and reviewing of various contracts and agreements. Good communication skills with prior experience in US & UK clients interactions. Gathering biweekly timesheets and inputting information into payroll system and also process paperwork associated with new hires and terminated employees. Worked on financial software like Tungsten/OB10 for submitting weekly invoices. Actively working with the hiring department for the recruiting strategy and hiring needs. Managing sensitive and confidential data, personnel files and documents of employees. A committed team player with ability to deliver projects within schedule and can work on multiple tasks in a fast paced environment.

Work History

HR/Payroll Coordinator, 01/2014 to Current

Forward Air Solutions â€" Hammond , LA

- Create and submit 12 reports to manager bi-weekly along with time sheets of the consultants and also enter consultant's hours into the Time Reporting system for payroll processing.
- Act as the liaison between employees, payments, and the Payroll Manager.
- Responsible for all data entry into the payroll system including direct deposit, W-4 and new hire information and Process and verify payment
 of invoices on a timely basis.
- Submit consultant's invoices bi-weekly through financial software (Tungsten); Managing full cycle recruitment process which includes sourcing candidates; screening applications, arranging interviews and administering pre-employment tests as required.
- Handling complete paperwork for on-boarding consultants (which includes NDA, Contractor Action Form) Assist with benefits questions, as needed.
- Run background and credit checks; maintain and prepares contract folders with all pertinent legal documents and paperwork of employees'
 personnel files.
- Provide customer service support to employees by answering questions and inquiries regarding company policies.
- Work in conjunction with senior management to ensure proper knowledge of all relative labor compliance topics and visa status.
- Draft and review Master Consulting Agreements & SOW between the company and consultants.
- Point of connection within the company between the line-of-business (LOB) and the IT department.
- Handle and update the company's online social media platforms.
- Research and work related to the process of affecting the visibility of the company's website through SEO management.
- Drafting of wire frame of new website and forward the contents through the company IT department.

Process Executive, 04/2011 to 09/2012

Bank Of America Corporation â€" Coeur D Alene

- Infosys Ltd is the top Indian IT Company.
- Worked related to Tracking of Legal Obligations and Risk Assessment in Master Service Agreements of Infosys Limited's Global clients;
 Communicated actively with various US & UK clients; Drafted and reviewed various Software Licensing Agreements, Non-Disclosure
 Agreements, Work Orders, Statement of Work and Business Agreements; Reviewed 5 Master Software Agreements of various US's &
 UK clients per week; Worked on domains related to Customer Relationship Management (CRM) Platform; Prepared a standard template
 for contract management for my entire team which helped in saving lot of time of my colleagues during obligations' tracking from Master
 Contracts.
- This was very much applauded by senior management and this tempalte was distributed amongst all team members.

Legal Associate, 06/2009 to 03/2011

Metropolitan Bank Holding Corp. â€" New York

- Worked in total 5 projects relating to contentious & non-contentious Intellectual Property Rights; Drafted, vetted and reviewed almost 4 different varieties of contracts every month.
- Drafted 2 "Service Agreements" and 'Representation and Warranties' of a Share Subscription Agreement.
- Drafted total 4 Memorandum of Associations and Article of Associations for 2 different organizations.
- Research work on a detailed & complete due diligence of a MNC's merger & acquisition process.

Assistant Teacher, 12/2008 to 05/2009

New York Kids Club

• for "Corporate Mergers, Acquisitions and Reconstruction", Bangalore, India.

Education MBA: 4 2015

Northwestern Polytechnic University - City, State

Bachelor of Law: 5 2009

Bishop Cotton Women's Christian Law College, Bangalore University -

Certifications

Certified Social Media Professional (Marketing Certified University, Santa Clara, CA) Diploma in Intellectual Property Rights (Asian School of Cyber Law) Diploma in Corporate Mergers, Acquisitions and Reconstruction (Asian School of Cyber Law) Diploma in Securities and

Investments (Indian Institute of Law)

Affiliations

Competent Communicator and Member of International Toastmasters Club, California. Community Service: Volunteered at India Community Service during Summer Camp, 2014, Milpitas, CA Volunteered in Society for Socio-Economic Awareness and Environment Protection (SSEAP) from 25th May to 20

Skills

Acquisitions, benefits, bi, CA, consultant, Consulting, contract management, Contracts, credit, Customer Relationship Management, CRM, clients, customer service, data entry, Drafting, due diligence, senior management, financial, frame, Investments, Law, Legal, Managing, Marketing, Mergers, MS Excel, MS Power Point, MS Word, Payroll, payroll processing, personnel, policies, recruitment, Reporting, Research, Risk Assessment, Securities, website